usenet.nl 2017-02-27

# Usenet.nl - privacy statement

Should you have questions concerning privacy that are not answered in this statement, please contact us at the following addresses. 

Management: usenet.nl is offered by   
Usenet.nl S.r.l., Via XXV Marzo, 4   
47895 Domagnano, San Marino

Manager: Giacomo Boria  
Service form

### 1\. Data reading, processing and use for the intended purposes and in other specific cases.

Various data is read, processed and eventually saved when using Usenet.nl. 

Should you visit our pages without registering, Usenet.nl shall only read access data without any personal reference such as, for example, the IP address, the internet address of the pages from which you reached our site, the name of the file requested and pooling time.

Personal data is only read when you voluntarily provide it upon site or newsletter registration. Personal data is considered: surname and name, address, telephone number, e-mail address and payment data. Naturally, you can change any information should actual conditions change in time. Additional data includes your user name and password used to login and any other user settings.

Your personal data will be forwarded by us to the service providers used for the various services (customer service, payment service, bank).

Your data will be stored for as long as you hold a user account with Usenet.nl and data must be available under the contract to meet the storage obligations required by law. Data will be deleted when storage conditions are no longer met and at the end of legal storage obligations.

Personal data will only be used by us for the purposes specified below:

  1. use of services offered by Usenet.nl, including advertising via e-mail, provided this is authorised by the user.
  2. additionally, to further develop our services, we save and process data to efficiently manage our services.

Your personal data will only be read, saved, processed and used for the above purposes. Your data will be deleted as soon as the required purpose is fulfilled. This, in exceptional cases, does not only occur in the event and to the extent in which legal provisions include storage obligations.

Individuals to whom data may be communicated to meet contract obligations with customers are outsourced service providers as per the German Federal Privacy law § 11 (BDSG). Furthermore, any data that can be used to trace back to you are sent to third parties (for example, investigating authorities), without your explicit prior authorisation, on in the event mandatory legal conditions apply.

### 2\. Security and liability

Data stored on our servers are protected by us, within technical possibilities, through constantly updated data protection software. Specifically, particularly sensitive data is transmitted using an advanced security standard (TLS technology).

To the extent with which you use our customer forum or are logged into Usenet, you share certain information with third parties. Please note that you are solely liable for the communication of your information and therefore independently take on the associated risks. Personal information as well as comments, communications and other contributions you post are publically available. We cannot be held liable to this effect.

These data privacy provisions exclusively apply for Usenet.nl internet offer purposes. We do not have any influence on Usenet content. Therefore, we cannot be held liable to this effect. The same applies to the reading, processing and use of your data by third parties: here too, in fact, we do not have any influence and thus cannot be held liable in any way.

### 3\. Cookies

When you open the Usenet.nl website we send your computer one or more so-called cookies. The purpose of cookies is to adapt the Usenet.nl range as effectively as possible to your needs and make our website more interesting for you. A cookie is a small text file containing a specific character sequence that univocally identifies your browser. These cookies expire after 30 days and are not used for personal identification. Only when you tick the "Stay connected" box when logging in is a permanent cookie used (so-called persistent cookie) which is saved to give you faster access to your user area without having to login again. Our marketing partners are not allowed to read, process or use personal data via our website cookies. 

### 4\. Google Analytics

Our website uses the Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA) website analysis service, Google Analytics. This service uses so-called “cookies”. “Cookies” are text files that save the pages visited by your browser on your computer. This way, you authorise website use analysis. The information read by cookies (only your IP address) is generally sent to a Google server in the USA and saved there. The collected information is then used by Google to evaluate your website use. Reports are generated based on this information concerning website activities and other services connected to website use and exploitation are provided. Google may transmit the information to third parties, to the extent in which foreseen by law, meaning if Google assigns the processing of this data to third parties. In no case shall Google connect your IP address with other Google data. By using this website, you consent to the processing of your data read by Google as per the above methods and for the abovementioned purposes.

For further information on Google Analytics, please visit: <http://www.google.com/intl/en_uk/analytics/>

### 5\. Changing your data; newsletter registration

If you are already registered on usenet.nl, you can independently manage and update data concerning your name and address as well as newsletter delivery settings in your user area. For security reasons, you cannot change payment data here. If you changed this data and intend to inform us, you can do so using the support form or hotline.

Newsletter delivery and similar information (communications, advertisements) are exclusively subject to your prior explicit authorisation. Should you no longer wish to receive newsletter e-mails or similar information, you can cancel your subscription at any time, clicking on the cancel link at the bottom of the e-mail. Should you not be able to cancel your subscription using the specific link, please contact us via the support form, specifying the e-mail address that should be cancelled from the newsletter.

### 6\. Google AdWords and Google Display Network

Our website exploits online Google AdWords and Google Display Network promotion systems. On this topic, Google guarantees its customers and users’ data privacy. Google AdWords enables a cookie on your computer. The cookie only remains valid for 30 days and is not used to identify personal data. If the user visits certain pages in the AdWords customer’s website and the cookie has not yet expired, Google and the customer are able to recognise the user who clicked on the ad and who was sent to this page. This information is used to create statistics that are analysed in anonymous form. We also exploit these Google AdWords functions to address users on this website to third party websites or internet users with profiles of specific interest, based on their internet use. We do not collect any personal information to do this. In fact, any analyses are used to calculate and evaluate promo ads and do not contain your personal information. Users who do not intend to participate in localisation may simply deactivate the Google Conversion-Tracking cookie in the internet browser user settings. These users will not be included in Conversion-Tracking statistics.

Please note that Google has its own guidelines concerning personal data privacy. We may not be held liable in any way for these guidelines and procedures. Please visit Google to learn more about their data privacy terms before using our website.

### 7\. Risk Ident GmbH

We employ the services of the IT Security Agency Risk Ident GmbH (Zippelhaus 2, 20457 Hamburg, Deutschland) for our website. All communication between us and Risk Ident takes place with the sole purpose of combating fraud when using our website.

#### a) Data Storage

Risk Ident collects and processes specific data on our users about the configuration of the user’s end device (“device-specific data”), raw data from the TCP/IP connection and data on the use of our website. In the process, tracking technology, such as cookies and JavaScript elements and Shockwave Flash objects are used which are integrated into the website. Cookies are text files which save the visited website via the browser onto your computer and which contain information about the use of this website. The JavaScript and Shockwave Flash objects make it possible to read information on the user’s end device, which is automatically transmitted after each internet session. For technical reasons, the user’s IP address is collected and processed by Risk Ident and encoded by Risk Ident within seconds. Risk Ident saves the information anonymously onto a databank for fraud prevention.

#### b) Data Retrieval

Whenever a user concludes a contract or aims to conclude a contract over our website, e.g. by setting up a user account or by beginning the check-out process in order to buy a certain item, we call up a risk assessment on Risk Ident’s databank which has been saved there for the user’s end device. This risk assessment, based inter alia on information ascertains (a) if the user’s end device is currently communicating or has communicated in the past a proxy connection, (b) if the end device has recently dialed into various internet service providers, (c) if the end device exhibits or has exhibited a frequent change in geo-reference, (d) how many internet transactions have been made in recent weeks (whereby we are not informed about the type of transaction), and (e) how probable it is that the end device saved in the Risk Ident data bank really belongs to the user. (The result of this risk assessment helps us to prevent fraud on our website. The data, however, is not a sole criterion to either complete or terminate a purchase).

### 8\. Survey Tools

Customer satisfaction surveys are carried out using a tool supplied by an external service provider (SurveyMonkey). Please ensure that the provider of this tool implements its own [ data protection strategy](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/policy/privacy-policy/). Participation in customer surveys is voluntary. The customer survey is configured so that IP addresses or e-mails are not collected automatically. E-mail addresses will not be disclosed to third parties. The SurveyMonkey website uses Cookies. More about the different kinds of cookies used on this Website, please click [here](http://help.surveymonkey.com/articles/en_US/kb/About-the-cookies-we-use).
